Thorvald F. Hammer Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
- Series V: Reference Materials, 1892-1982
  - Publications about hot dip galvanizing, 1940-1974 (Box 12:, Folder 341)
  - Standards and Specifications, 1930-1959 (Box 12:, Folder 342)
  - Steel Founders' Society: constitution and by-laws, 1952, 1964 (Box 12:, Folder 343)
  - Valve Manufacturers' Association Report, 1943 (Box 12:, Folder 344)
  - Company Catalogs and Price Lists
    - A — I, 1900-1970 (Box 13)
    - J — Z, 1900-1970 (Box 14)
- Series VI: Memorabilia, Biographical and Historical Records, undated, 1854-1987
  - T.F. Hammer biographical information, 1945-1987 (Box 15:, Folder 345)
  - T.F. Hammer consultant advertisements, ca. 1970-1980 (Box 15:, Folder 346)
  - T.F. Hammer's notes on annealing of steel process, undated (Box 15:, Folder 347)
  - MIF Co. historical information: published, 1927-1954 (Box 15:, Folder 348-349)
  - MIF Co. historical information: unpublished, 1854-1954 (Box 15:, Folder 350)
  - Photographs
    - A.E. Hammer, undated (Box 16:, Folder 351)
    - T.F. Hammer, undated (Box 16:, Folder 352)
    - Old timers group, 1951 (Box 16:, Folder 353)
    - Malleable Founders Society, undated (Box 16:, Folder 354)
    - Storm and flood damage, 1954 (Box 16:, Folder 355)
    - Machinery and factory site, undated (Box 16:, Folder 354)
    - Aerial photo of factory area, undated (Box 16:, Folder 355)
    - Drawing of factory site, ca. 1860-1900 (Box 16:, Folder 356)
  - 100th Anniversary commemorative souvenir, 1954 (Box 16:, Folder 357)
  - MIF Co. product samples: pipes, joints and fittings (Box 17:, Folder 358)
  - Drawings and Blueprints
    - Acid tanks and pickle barrels for ITT, Grinnell Corporation, 1973 (Box 17:, Folder 359)
    - Drossing scoop, 1972 (Box 17:, Folder 360)
    - Galvanizing facility for Edward Bounds, 1977 (Box 17:, Folder 361)
    - Galvanizing facility for Udylite Company, 1975 (Box 17:, Folder 362)
    - Galvanizing machine for ITT, Grinnell Corporation, 1973 (Box 17:, Folder 363)
    - Kettle for ITT, Grinnell Corporation, 1973 (Box 17:, Folder 364)
    - Proposed alterations to Birch Hill Foundries Inc.: galvanizing Facilities, 1976 (Box 17:, Folder 365)
    - Proposed galvanizing facilities for Gustin Bacon Division Of Certainteed, 1973; (2 drawings) (Box 17:, Folder 366)
    - Proposed galvanizing facility for nails Infasco, Division of Ivaco, 1979 (Box 17:, Folder 367)
      (TexasGulf)
    - Proposed galvanizing facilities for Nibco de Mexico, S.A., 1976 (Box 17:, Folder 368)
    - Proposed galvanizing facilities for Star Galvanizing Division Of Midland Forge, 1977 (Box 17:, Folder 369)
    - Proposed galvanizing facility for TexasGulf Inc. (Ivaco), 1978; (3 drawings) (Box 17:, Folder 370)
    - Proposed layout for rack automation of 22 foot galvanizing (Box 17:, Folder 371)
    - Kettle for Stanley G. Flagg and Company, Inc., 1975 (Box 17:, Folder 372)
    - Stripper (preliminary layout), 1973 (Box 17:, Folder 373)
    - Suggested design for manual operated galvanizing facility for Nibco de Mexico, 1977 (Box 17:, Folder 374)
    - Untitled drawing, 1974 (Box 17:, Folder 375)
    - Untitled drawing, 1976 (Box 17:, Folder 376)
    - Untitled drawing, undated (Box 17:, Folder 377)
  - Models
    The Thorvald F. Hammer Papers contain several models created by Mr. Hammer as part of his consultant practice. These models are primarily of various facets of the malleable iron casting process. The exact purpose or date of construction of these models is, however, undeterminable because of a lack of information. In all, there are six models, four of which are free standing and two of which are in boxes.